# **Drew Morgan**



19 Lowbrook Avenue, Manchester, M9 7JD

.NET | C# | VB | Python | MVVM | MVC | WCF/WPF | XAML | HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript | SQL | IIS AJAX | JSON | XSLT | SOLID | Dependency Injection | Git | SVN | TFS | Agile | Linux | Windows Artificial Intelligence | Computer Vision | Data Analysis | Data Modelling | Mentoring | MS Office

#### Introduction

Confident, creative and hard-working, I have eight years of professional programming experience and have been coding as a hobby since childhood. I have mostly been exposed to Microsoft products but enjoy learning new things. In my first role I developed web-based systems in the healthcare space, including prescribing and diagnostic data. I then trained as a physics teacher and taught for 4 years before returning to software development and catching up with modern technology and standards.

# **Work Experience**

# bet365 - Software Developer

(~2 years) July 2018 – Present

C#, VB, MVVM, XAML, SQL, SOLID, DI, Git, Jira

Worked on the Generic eSports InPlay and DOTA 2 IP tools, involving tying together multiple services to communicate data across different teams' systems. Ended up as the point of contact for the generic eSports tool and was one of the few people who understood Italy market mapping. The DOTA 2 team became known as the 'dream team' as we ended up 4 months ahead of schedule with just two developers and a tech lead.

# PayStream - Developer

(~3 years) Sept 2015 – July 2018

C#, VB, MVC, XAML, HTML5, CSS, JS, SQL, IIS, XSLT, SOLID, DI, Git, TFS

Developed internal and client-facing systems, including the web portal, and mentored juniors. Changes were usually to add new use cases following company acquisitions or new legislation. Re-styled the web portal, created a new system for CRMs and sales managers, and greatly improved existing applications.

# **Utilisoft** – .**NET Developer**

(3 months) Jun 2015 - Aug 2015

C#, VB, VB6, ASP, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL, JSON, XML, SVN, Data Analysis

Using VB.NET and ASP.NET but integrating with VB6, wrote an audit system for industry-standard XML messages, and helped to reengineer the billing system to allow for more control.

# Bury College – Web and Database Development Supervisor C#, ASP, MVC, HTML5, CSS, JS, SQL, IIS, AJAX, SVN, Mentoring

(~ 1 year) July 2014 – Jun 2015

Managed a 2-strong team who developed, supported and maintained over twenty college-wide data management systems used for student applications, interviews, enrolment and teaching support.

Introduced source control, data layers/stored procedures, a basic deployment pipeline, and testing.

**Teaching** Data Analysis, Mentoring, MS Office

(~4 years) Aug 2010 - July 2014

#### X-Lab – Developer, Service Quality Manager

(~2.5 years) Jan 2008 – Aug 2010

C#, MVC, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL, SVN, Data Modelling, MS Office

Along with development of the core system, my roles included prototyping, business analysis, credit control, payroll, documentation, tenders, contracts and presentations. Over two and a half years I built up a client base covering 250 UK laboratories, contributed to a nationwide benchmarking project investigating links between diagnostic testing and disease prevalence, and developed the first freely accessible browser for the Systematized Nomenclature of Medicine.

#### **Education**

# **University of Leeds**

PGCE Secondary Physics (QTS with Masters credits) (1 year 5 months) Aug 2010 — Dec 2011

**University of Leeds** 

Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence (2:1) (3 years) Aug 2004 — July 2007

**University of Leeds** 

Physics Single Hons (Incomplete) (2 years) Aug 2002 — July 2004

# **Other Achievements and Activities**

•	2020	Benevolent Leader	CodeWith
•	2020	Diving Officer	Manchester University Sub Aqua Club
•	2017	Dive Leader, Assistant Instructor	British Sub Aqua Club (BSAC)
•	2017	Host/Mentor	CodeUp Manchester
•	2007	BIT'94 Prize	University of Leeds Computing Department
•	2005-07	Treasurer, then President	Leeds University Union Computing Society
•	2004-05	Treasurer	Leeds University Union Jiu Jitsu Society
•	2001	Grade 7 Piano, Grade 8 Tuba	ABRSM
•	1999	Best News Presenter/Team	KIC FM (co-hosted a youth radio show)

# **Skills and Experience**

I have a strong subject knowledge of computing, maths and physics, and a passion for science and technology. I started coding aged 8, and over the years have written desktop and web applications, built computers, coded Lego robots making use of circuitry and sensors, played with libraries like PyGame and OpenCV, written basic genetic algorithms and neural networks and attempted to build knowledge processing systems. I try to keep up to date with innovations in science and artificial intelligence, and always welcome the opportunity to learn.

#### **Personal**

In the evenings I can usually be found at home working on a programming project or playing music or up a wall in a climbing centre, and once a month will be seen at CodeUp showing and/or teaching people something about programming. At weekends I'm often underwater in a quarry somewhere.

I like to know how and why things work, and have an innate curiosity about the world. I enjoy learning new skills and relish the opportunity to stand up and present my passions to other people.

I started learning to play music aged five and now play piano, tuba, guitar and clarinet. In 2005 I wrote an 8-minute piece for orchestra, which was performed by the Wolverhampton Youth Orchestra the following year during their European tour.

#### Web

CodeUp Manchester <a href="https://codeupmanchester.github.io/">https://codeupmanchester.github.io/</a>

CodeWith https://codewith.org.uk/

GitHub <a href="https://github.com/dangerworm">https://github.com/dangerworm</a>

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/drew-morgan-44929190

RUBSAC Lectures https://rubsac.github.io/